Guide to the Mary McMillan papers, 1936-1997 and undated, bulk 1952-1991 RL.00881
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material Series, 1936-1997 and undated
  Consists primarily of newsletters, pamphlets, flyers, and church bulletins. It is divided into five subseries, based on the primary subject content of the material: Hiroshima and Japan, Topaz Relocation Center, Church, Peace Activism, and Other Activism. Material is arranged chronologically within the subseries. Also included in the list are three books that have been cataloged separately and are housed in the Special Collections stacks. Items in Japanese have been noted in the list below.
  - Hiroshima and Japan Subseries, 1936-1991 and undated
    Includes biographies or memoirs of Japanese citizens or others influential in Japanese society, books and pamphlets about the history of Hiroshima, numerous college catalogs from Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College, and journals and newsletters documenting the life of Japanese-Americans.
    - 1936, Gaines Sensei: Missionary to Hiroshima Samuel M. Hilburn (Box 12)
    - 1952, Peace City Hiroshima, no author (Box 12)
    - 1956 Oct., The Story of Hiroshima Jo Gakuin, Kaizo Odagiri (Box 12)
    - 1958 Mar., Ei Bun Gakkai Kai Ho (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1959 Aug. 6, Peace Memorial ceremonies program (Box 12)
    - 1961 Aug., A Crane that Cannot Come Back, Nanako Seto (Box 12)
    - 1961 Nov., Hiroshima, the Atom, and the World, Earle L. Reynolds (Box 12)
    - 1962, Japan for Christ - Christ for All Japan, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 12)
    - 1962 Apr. 10, The Torch, Vol. 1, No. 9, student newspaper of Hiroshima Jo Gakuin (Box 12)
    - 1964 Nov., The Rivers of Hiroshima, no author (Box 12)
    - 1968,Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1968, Dr. Takuo Matsumoto and Hiroshima, Takuo Matsumoto (Box 12)
    - 1969 June, Goodbye to Hiroshima: Barbara Reynolds, YMCA Hiroshima (Box 12)
    - 1970, Hiroshima Declaration, 1970 Hiroshima Conference (Box 12)
    - 1971,Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - Hiroshima Citizens Congress to Prevent French Nuclear Testing statement, 1973 Mar. (Box 12)
    - 1976,United Church of Christ in Japan budget (Box 12)
    - 1977,Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1977 July, Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum, Hiroshima Appeal Committee (Box 12)
    - 1978 Aug., The Outline of Atomic Bomb Damage in Hiroshima, Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum (Box 12)
    - 1979,Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1980 Mar. 15, Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College Dagaku Sotsugyo (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1980 May, Hiroshima Signpost (Box 12)
    - 1981, City Planning of Hiroshima (Box 12)
    - 1982,Statement made by Hitoshi Motoshima, Mayor of Nagasaki, at the NGO Session of the U.N. General Assembly Devoted to Disarmament (Box 12)
    - 1982 Aug. 6, No More Hiroshimas flyer (Box 12)
    - 1982 Dec. 31, Devotion of Hiroshima to the Cause of Peace, City of Hiroshima (Box 12)
    - 1983, Hiroshima Surgeon Tomin Harada (Box 12)
    - 1984 June, YUWA, by the Japan section of the International Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box 12)
    - 1984 Dec., Asian Rural Institute Bulletin, Vol. 4, No. 1 (Box 12)
    - 1985,Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1985,Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1986, The Legacy of Hiroshima: Its Past, Our Future, Naomi Shohno (Box 12)
    - 1986 Sept. 30, Do So Sei No Yo Be (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1986 Nov. 3, Memorial service for the late Rev. Kiyoshi Tanimoto (program) (Box 12)
    - 1989, Hando Bukko, (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1989 Apr. 1, 1989-1990 Mar. 31, Asian Rural Institute: Annual Report on the 1989 Rural Leaders Training Program (Box 12)
    - 1989 Apr. 16,Church bulletin (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1989 July, ARI Newsletter, Asian Rural Institute (Box 12)
    - 1990, There is a Spirit: The Nayler Sonnets, Sonnets on Courtship, Marriage, and Family Kenneth Boulding, translated by Nobuyuki Yuasa (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1990,Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1990 Jan., NJAHS Focus, Vol. 6, No. 1, National Japanese American Historical Society (Box 12)
    - 1990 July, NJAHS Focus, Vol. 6, No. 4, National Japanese American Historical Society (Box 12)
    - 1990 Sept. 29, Hiroshima Jo Gakuin Chu Gakko Kosha (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - 1991 May 29,Gen dai ni i kiru... (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - undated, Death Data of the Victims from August 1959 to May 1960, no author (Box 12)
    - undated, God be with you Till we Meet Again, Jeremiah Eames Rankin (Box 12)
    - undated, Hiroshima: For Picture Postcard, author unknown (Box 12)
    - undated, Hiroshima Girls School catalog (Box 12)
    - undated, Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (Box 12)
    - undated, Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College catalog (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - undated, Hiroshima: Peace Memorial City, Hiroshima Peace Culture Center (Box 12)
    - undated, Hiroshima Peace Park and Rally in Tokyo, no author (Box 12)
    - undated, History of Ushita Church (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - undated, Map of Hiroshima (Box 12)
    - undated, Schedule for the International Christian Peace Conference (Box 12)
    - undated, The Japan Cultural Society of Northwest Florida Newsletter, Vol. 2, No. 3 (Box 12)
    - undated, Japan Studies: New Focus on the Japanese Mind and Culture, Vol. 1, Nos. 7-9, 11 (Box 12)
    - undated, The Japanese American Experience, National Japanese American Historical Society (Box 12)
    - undated, Memorial Cathedral for World Peace, published by the Catholic Church (Box 12)
    - undated, Mission School in Hiroshima, author unknown (Box 12)
    - undated, Program to Promote Solidarity of Cities Towards the Total Abolition of Nuclear Weapons, City of Hiroshima and the City of Nagasaki (Box 12)
    - undated, To the Mothers and Wives of the United States, from Japanese Women (Box 12)
    - undated, To the Representatives who are Gathered in Hiroshima from Around the World to Attend the 5th Anti-A and H-Bombs World Conference, by the Hiroshima Committee for Protecting Children (Box 12)
    - undated, Ho Shi Dan Towa? (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - undated, Kotobaki - Nakagawa, Kishi (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - undated, Hiroshima Jo Gakuin Genbaku Giseishya Meibo (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - undated, Heiwa No Uta (in Japanese) (Box 12)
    - undated, Postcards of Hiroshima (Box 12)
  - Topaz Relocation Center Subseries, 1988
    Contains two programs published in conjunction with the 1988 reunion held by those who were interned at the camp.
    - 1988 Sept. 16-1988 Sept. 18,Topaz reunion program (Box 12)
    - 1988 Sept. 16-1988 Sept. 18,Topaz reunion booklet of photographs and addresses (Box 12)
  - Church Subseries, 1937-1997 and undated
    Primarily documents the work of the Methodist Church as well as the National Christian Council of Japan and the Kyodan in the Japanese society. Church bulletins, from Japan and the United States, are also included. Primary publications represented include The Methodist Witness, Japan Christian Activity News, Kyodan Newsletter, and The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin. Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1937 Dec., The Lifesharer, Christmas Issue, Vol. VIII, No. 2, Students of Scarritt College for Christian Workers (Box 13)
    - 1942 Jan. 16,First Congregational Church (Berkeley, Calif.) bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1943 Oct. 24,The University Church Bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1949 Oct.-Dec.,The Methodist Youth Fund Bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1954 Apr. 16, No Man Can Serve Two Masters, author unknown (Box 13)
    - 1955 Aug., Peaceful Coexistence: The Christian Obligation Kathleen Linsdale, published by the East-West Relations Committee of the Religious Society of Friends (Box 13)
    - 1958 Feb. 22, Does the Bible Sanction War?, M. Guy West, published by the Church of the Brethren (Box 13)
    - 1959 July 15, Japan Christian Activity News, No. 150, Commission on Public Relations of the National Christian Council of Japan (Box 13)
    - 1963, Fall, Bulletin, Vol. I, No. 2, Ecumenical Department, Research Institute on the Mission of the Church, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1968 July, Policy Statements and Statistics of the United Church of Christ in Japan (Kyodan), author unknown (Box 13)
    - 1970 Mar. 6,World Day of Prayer flyer (Box 13)
    - 1971 Oct. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1974 Jan.-Feb., The Upper Room, Vol. 39, No. 6 (Box 13)
    - 1974 Mar. 1, World Day of Prayer service bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1978 July 28, Japan Christian Activity News, No. 539, Commission on Public Relations of the National Christian Council of Japan (Box 13)
    - 1979 Mar. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 133, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1979 Apr. 27, Japan Christian Activity News, No. 548, Commission on Public Relations of the National Christian Council of Japan (Box 13)
    - 1980 Sept., The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin, No. 300, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1981 Aug. 6,Hiroshima Remembered bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1981 Sept. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 158, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1981 Nov.-Dec., The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin, No. 312, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1981 Dec. 10, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 160, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1982 Apr. 29, Pastoral Letter by the Council of Bishops of the United Methodist Church (Box 13)
    - 1982 Aug. 22, Japan Christian Activity News, No. 588, Commission on Public Relations of the National Christian Council of Japan (Box 13)
    - 1983 Feb. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 172, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1983 Mar. 22; 1983 May 25; 1984 Jan. 20, Japan Christian Activity News, Nos. 595, 597, 605, Commission on Public Relations of the National Christian Council of Japan (Box 13)
    - 1984 Sept. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 188, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1985 Mar. 1, Church Women United Bulletin, Church Women United of the United States of America (Box 13)
    - 1985 Sept., The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin, No. 350, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1986, In Defense of the Creation: The Nuclear Crisis and a Good Peace, United Methodist Council of Bishops:
      - Foundation Document (Box 13)
      - Pastoral Letter (Box 13)
      - Guide for Study and Action (Box 13)
    - 1986 Dec. 10, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 210, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1988, They That Hope in God, Margaret Warren (Box 13)
    - 1988 Apr. 20, May 20; 1990 Jan. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, Nos. 224, 225, 241, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1990 Mar.-Apr., The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin, No. 386, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1990 Mar. 20, June 20, Kyodan Newsletter, Nos. 243, 246 United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1990 June-July, The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin, No. 388, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1990 July 20, Oct. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 247, 249 United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1990 Nov.-Dec., The Kyodan Missionary Bulletin, No. 390, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1990 Dec. 20, Kyodan Newsletter, No. 250, United Church of Christ in Japan (Box 13)
    - 1990 Dec. 20, Koinonia Newsletter, No. 250 (Box 13)
    - 1991 Oct. 18-Oct. 19,AL West FL Conference, United Methodist Women, 19th Annual Meeting Program (Box 13)
    - 1995 July 16; Aug. 6, 13, 20; Sept. 10, The Methodist Witness, Vol. 174, Nos. 34, 37-39, 42, Pensacola First United Methodist Church (Box 13)
    - 1995 Sept. 17,Pensacola First United Methodist Church bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1995 Oct. 1; 1997 July 27, The Methodist Witness, Vol. 174, No. 45; Vol 177, No. 30, Pensacola First United Methodist Church (Box 13)
    - undated, Affirmation of Faith, author unknown (Box 13)
    - undated, Celebrating the Birth of Christ, Alternatives Christmas Campaign (Box 13)
    - undated, Japan Listens for a Voice, Baker James Couthen, published by the Baptist Foreign Mission Board (Box 13)
    - undated, Kyodan Newsletter Presents the Problem of Church Renewal in Japan Today, Masahisa Suzuki (Box 13)
    - undated, Scarritt-Bennett Center brochure (Box 13)
    - undated, Seirei En flyer, no author (Box 13)
    - undated, Serve God in Japan, Council on Cooperative Mission (Box 13)
    - undated, Who Will Build the World Anew?, Thomas C. Clark and Richard Redhead (Box 13)
  - Peace Activism Subseries, 1959-1997 and undated
    Consists primarily of newsletters from organizations promoting world peace and nuclear disarmament, such as the Alternative World Foundation, the Center for Defense Information, the Council for a Livable World, War Resisters' League, and the World Friendship Center. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1959 June-July, No More Hiroshimas!: The News of the Japan Council Against A and H Bombs, Vol. 6, Nos. 4, 5 (Box 13)
    - 1959 Aug. 12, FCNL Action, No. 22, Friends Committee on National Legislation (Box 13)
    - 1967 Dec., Information Bulletin of the Christian Peace Conference, No. 43 (Box 13)
    - 1968 Mar., A Quaker Action Group Newsletter, No. 10 (Box 13)
    - 1970 May 9, You Don't Have to Buy War, Mrs. Smith, Bess Myerson Grant (Box 13)
    - 1970 June,Draft resistance brochure (Box 13)
    - 1970, Another Mother for Peace: Summer Summary (Box 13)
    - 1970 Sept-Oct., WRL News, No. 161, War Resisters League (Box 13)
    - 1974 June, Center Report, Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 13)
    - 1977 Feb.,Another Mother for Peace flyer (Box 13)
    - 1977 Winter,World Friendship Center bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1977 Mar. 7, WFC Minutes, World Friendship Center (Box 13)
    - 1978 Mar. 6,Kobe Union Church bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1978 Summer, Winter,World Friendship Center bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1980 Mar. 3, WFC Minutes, World Friendship Center (Box 13)
    - 1980 July, Disarming Notes, Vol. II, No. 9, published by the Riverside Church (Box 13)
    - 1982 June, We Appeal to the Whole World, Kazumitsu Aihara (Box 13)
    - 1983 Jan. 28, Peacemaking: A Musical Play, Ruth Taylor Saito and Margaret L. Warren (Box 13)
    - 1983 Feb., Communism, the Churches, and the Peace Movement: A Response by the Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box 13)
    - 1983 Spring, The Mobilizer, Vol. 3, No. 1, published by Mobilization for Survival (Box 13)
    - 1983 May,Union of Concerned Scientists pledge bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1983 Summer, WPTF Newsletter, Vol. X, No. 2, published by the National Campaign for a World Peace Tax Fund (Box 13)
    - 1984, The Defense Monitor, Vol. XIII, No. 6, published by the Center for Defense Information (Box 13)
    - 1984 Summer, Legislative Alert, published by the National Peace Academy Campaign (Box 13)
    - 1984 Fall,World Friendship Center bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1984 Sept.-Oct., WRL News, No. 244, published by the War Resisters League (Box 13)
    - 1984 Dec.,Union of Concerned Scientists pledge bulletin (Box 13)
    - 1986, 1986-87 F.O.R. National Council Ballot, published by the Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box 13)
    - 1986 Summer, Peace Tax Fund Newsletter, No. 3, published by the National Campaign for a World Peace Tax Fund (Box 13)
    - 1990,World Friendship Center bulletin, Vol. 3 and 4 (Box 13)
    - 1990 Mar.,Council for a Livable World newsletter (Box 13)
    - 1990 Aug., Daniel Kahikina Akaka of Hawaii, published by the Council for a Livable World (Box 13)
    - 1990 Aug., The Reporter for Conscience Sake, Vol. XLVII, No. 7, published by the National Interreligious Service Board for Conscientious Objectors (Box 13)
    - 1990 Sept., CFU International, Vol. 10, No. 3 (Box 13)
    - 1991 Jan.-Feb., Social Questions Bulletin, Vol. 81, No. 1, published by the Methodist Federation for Social Action (Box 13)
    - 1991 Apr., The Reporter for Conscience Sake, Vol. XLVIII, No. 4, published by the National Interreligious Service Board for Conscientious Objectors (Box 13)
    - 1992, World Friendship Center Newsletter, No. 85, Vol. 2 (Box 13)
    - 1993; 1995 Nov.-Dec., The Defense Monitor, Vol. XXII, Nos. 8-9; Vol. XXIV, No. 9, published by the Center for Defense Information (Box 13)
    - 1996 Jan., Peace Pac Newsletter (Box 13)
    - 1997 May and July,Council for a Livable World newsletters (Box 13)
    - 1997 June, The Defense Monitor, Vol. XXVI, No. 3, published by the Center for Defense Information (Box 13)
    - undated, The Civilized Defense Plan, published by the Alternative World Foundation (Box 13)
    - undated, Freeze Lobby Action Alert Network, published by the National Freeze Campaign (Box 13)
    - undated, Gifts of the Holy Spirit, Harriett Miller (Box 13)
    - undated, Join a National Peace Organization, author unknown (Box 13)
    - undated, New Zealand: An Ally for the Peace Movement, published by the New England Pacific Coalition (Box 13)
    - undated, O Innocent Child, Thich Nhat Hanh (Box 13)
    - undated, An Orientation to a World Beyond War, author unknown (Box 13)
    - undated, Reflections on Daniel Berrigan: Upon Seeing the Picture of his Capture, Robert McAfee Brown (Box 13)
    - undated, A Time to Act, published by the National Council for a World Peace Tax Fund (Box 13)
    - undated, The United States Already has 26,000 Nuclear Warheads, published by the Council for a Livable World (Box 13)
    - undated, We Object to the Peace Declaration, published by the Hiroshima Citizens Group (Box 13)
    - undated, World Friendship Center Bulletin (Box 13)
    - undated, World Peace Pledge, published by the Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box 13)
  - Other Activism Subseries, 1971-1997 and undated
    Contains material documenting McMillan's other activism efforts, including the promotion of justice and literacy. This subseries consists primarily of issues of the Washington Spectator, a liberal activists' publication produced by the Public Concern Foundation, an organization which reports on political activities in Washington, D.C. Arranged in date order.
    - 1971 Jan.-June Pax et Libertas, Vol. 36, Nos. 1-2, published by the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box 13)
    - 1980 Apr. 15, Aug. 15, Dec. 1, The Washington Spectator, Vol. 6, Nos. 7, 14, and 21, published by the Public Concern Foundation (Box 13)
    - 1982 Spring, Humanities, Vol. 8, published by the Virginia Foundation for the Humanities and Public Policy (Box 13)
    - 1984 Sept. 15, The Washington Spectator, Vol. 20, No. 10, published by the Public Concern Foundation (Box 13)
    - 1986, 1986 Campaign Strategy Sheet, author unknown (Box 13)
    - 1989 Feb. 28,United Methodist Women Executive Committee meeting schedule (Box 13)
    - 1990 Oct., Laubach Literacy International Newsletter, Vol. 1, No. 3 (Box 13)
    - 1990 Oct. 16-Oct. 24,Peace with Justice Week flyer (Box 13)
    - 1991,Chautauqua newsletter, published by the Chautauqua Institution (Box 13)
    - 1991 Spring and Winter, Pendle Hill Bulletin, Nos. 380 and 383 (Box 13)
    - 1996 Aug. 15, Oct. 15; 1997 Mar. 15, The Washington Spectator, Vol. 22, Nos. 17, 19; Vol. 23, No. 6, published by the Public Concern Foundation (Box 13)
    - 1997 Apr., ADA Today, Vol. 52, No. 1 (Box 13)
    - undated, Resist pamphlet, author unknown (Box 13)
    - undated, An Indian Prayer, author unknown (Box 13)
- Clippings About Peace Activism Series, 1960-1997 and undated (Box 13)
  Contains one folder of newspaper and magazine clippings, primarily related to peace activism. A small number of clippings are in Japanese. The clippings, which are arranged chronologically, document the lingering effects of the atomic bomb on the people of Hiroshima, the Vietnam War, the growth of the United States' Star Wars defense system, and the conflict in the Middle East.
- Memorabilia Series, 1939-1991 and undated (Box 13)
  Contains five folders, whose contents include three Japanese-style paper dolls, an origami crane, and other small sketches and paintings; 15 business cards, primarily printed in both English and Japanese; three buttons collected from peace rallies or United Methodist Church meetings; and certificates presented to McMillan by various organizations for her social activism. Also included is a certificate presented to her after her voyage across the Pacific during her first trip to Japan in 1939. The final folder contains donation and membership cards, and documents the array of non-profit organizations with which McMillan was involved.
- Oversize Material Series, 1956-1991 and undated
  - Correspondence Subseries
    - Outgoing Correspondence Subseries, 1972 and undated, 2 items (Oversize-box 1)
    - Incoming Correspondence Subseries, 1959 and undated, 2 items (Oversize-box 1)
  - Writings and Speeches Subseries
    - Writings By Mary McMillan Subseries
      - 1971, Peace (Oversize-box 1)
      - undated, Handwritten notes (Oversize-box 1)
    - Writings By Others Subseries
      - 1958 Nov., Radiation and Human Welfare: Why Japan Objects [sic] the Nuclear Weapons Testing, Fusa Asaka (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1959 Aug. 1, General Report to the Preliminary Session of the 5th World Conference against Atomic and Hydrogen Bombs, Professor Kaoru Yasui (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1959 Aug. 7, The Movement against A and H Bombs in the Cultural Sphere in Hiroshima, Koichiro Tanabe (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1959 Aug. 7, The Report in Literature and the Problem of Peace, author unknown (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1969 Jan. 1, Statistics of Kirisutokyo Nenkan 1969, author unknown (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1970, A Dramalogue for the 25th Year of the Nuclear Age, author unknown (Oversize-box 1)
      - undated, Mary, Sue Severn (Oversize-box 1)
      - undated, My Life in Hiroshima, Doris Hartman (Oversize-box 1)
      - undated, Negotiation Now, a Petition Circulated by Vietnam Summer Japan, a New Group in Tokyo and Hiroshima, Concerned about the War in Vietnam (Oversize-box 1)
  - Printed Material Subseries
    - Hiroshima and Japan Subseries
      - 1956 Oct., The Story of Hiroshima Jo Gakuin, Kaizo Odagiri (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1959 Aug. 6,Peace Memorial ceremonies program (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1962, Japan for Christ - Christ for All Japan, United Church of Christ in Japan (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1962 Apr. 10, The Torch, Vol. 1, No. 9, student newspaper of Hiroshima Jo Gakuin College (Oversize-box 1)
      - undated, Death Data of the Victims from August 1959 to May 1960 (Oversize-box 1)
      - undated, Hiroshima Peace Park and Rally in Tokyo (Oversize-box 1)
      - Map of Hiroshima, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Church Subseries
      - 1974 Mar. 1,World Day of Prayer service bulletin (Oversize-box 1)
      - 1988, They That Hope in God, Margaret Warren (Oversize-box 1)
      - undated, Seirei En flyer, author unknown (Oversize-box 1)
    - Peace Activism Subseries
      - 1977 Mar. 7 and 1980 Mar. 3, WFC Minutes, World Friendship Center (Oversize-box 1)
  - Clippings About Peace Activism Subseries 1971-1991, 9 items (Oversize-box 1)
  - Memorabilia Subseries (Oversize-box 1)
    - Japanese calligraphy in red ink on unidentified material: quotation on peace, undated, 1 item (Oversize-box 1)
  - Clippings (Oversize-folder 2)